JOCELYN SHELTON

(404) 922-7393 • Shelton.Jocelyn@gmail.com • Atlanta, GA 30326 github.com/j22shelton

SUMMARY

Jr full stack web developer with Master's Degree able to merge credit analyst experience with full stack coding skills. Proven capability of making high quality analytical decisions under tight deadlines. World traveler with a passion for learning. Recent GA Tech Coding Bootcamp Graduate.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript ES5 & ES6, JQuery, Handlebars, API's, AJAX, Firebase, Node Servers, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Mongo, Mongoose, React, WordPress

Deployment: GitHub Pages, Heroku

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE: https://j22shelton.github.io/SheltonPortfolio/ (Please refer to site for additional projects)

Global Retirement Calculator, Project 3 (React Version):

https://retirement-calculator-24.herokuapp.com/ *Please allow sufficient time for the page to load*

- -Developed React app that allows users to find personally tailored international retirement solutions
- -Integrated Google OAuth user sign-in technology
- -Utilized MongoDB for persistent database storage
- -Incorporated Numbeo API to pull useful statistics from different cities to determine necessary calculations

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Aug 2019 Certificate in Coding, Full Stack Web Development
University of Connecticut, Aug 2011 Masters in Accounting, Accounting Scholarship, GPA 3.9
University of Miami, May 2002 BA in Psychology, Marketing Minor; J.F. P Scholarship, Dean's List, GPA 3.3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ANGEL OAK PRIME BRIDGE

Frontline Underwriter May 2018- Present

Atlanta, GA

Frontline underwriter for the Commercial Residential lending division. Underwrites short term renovation loans as well as long term investor cash flow mortgages. Significantly reduced portfolio risk by detecting fraudulent applications from a high volume broker.

*Received signing authority of \$750,000 within 2 weeks of employment

STATE FARM BANK

Frontline Underwriter Oct 2016- May 2018

Atlanta, GA

Fully underwrote residential mortgage loans on behalf of State Farm's Banking division using LOS software. Underwrote loans against both FNMA's guidelines as well as State Farm's private portfolio guidelines. Assisted with training loan officers.

*Completed 5 classes towards company sponsored CHFC designation

CLAYTON HOLDINGS, LLC (RADIAN PRIVATE MORTGAGE INSURANCE)

Residential Mortgage Underwriter Oct 2012- Sept 2016

Atlanta, GA

Underwrote loans for various different projects, ranging from Frontline, Due Diligence, and Collateral Residential mortgages, including Conventional, FHA, TX50(a)(6), and Non- Conforming loans. Worked as a back up team lead when needed. Audited the work of peers.

*Detected fraud resulting in termination of business with a client broker

WELLS FARGO, MORTGAGE DIVISION

Interim Underwriter Level 4 & 3 Sept 2011-Feb 2012; Aug 2010-April 2011

Saint Louis, MO

Responsible for frontline underwriting decisions on highest risk grade of mortgages. Communicated decisions to management, processors, and mortgage consultants. Regularly worked overtime while enrolled in graduate school full time.

*Successfully tested to obtain highest level 4 underwriter title with 1 M authority.